Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Notice Period: 3 Months

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

PRIYABRAT PATTANAYAK (1) Featured

Application Development Senior Analyst seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Distribution Management, Production Support, Performance Tuning, SAP Implementation, Bug Tracking, Configuration Management, SAP ABAP



Current Designation: Application Development Senior Analyst

Current Company: Accenture

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Kolkata, Bhubaneshwar

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Application Development Senior Analyst, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Distribution Management, Production Support, Performance Tuning, SAP

Implementation, Bug Tracking, Configuration Management, SAP ABAP

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Having 5.3 Years of experience as an SAP ABAP IDOC techno-functional and EDI Consultant, currently working as an Application Development Senior Analyst in Accenture Solutions PVT LTD.

Working expertise in IDOC/ALE, Master Data Distribution, IDOC Development, Partner Profiles, Ports, RFC Destination, Distribution Model, Change Pointer, ALE Conversion Rule, Message Control.

Have worked on EDI IDOCs related to Sales and distribution, Order to Cash cycle, IC, FI modules.

Expertise in IDoc developments for ORDERS, ORDCHG, ORDRSP, DESADV, SHPCON, SHPMNT, INVOIC, DELJIT, DELFOR, STPPOD, LOIPRO messages.

Good knowledge in interface developments using Message Control.

Very strong experience on logistics and interfaces with TMS and WMS/LSP systems.

Have worked on IDocs related to SCD, VBD, Dangerous Goods, Inter Company, FI Masterdata,

Have worked on SAP EDI customer setup and SAP Order processing.

Work Experience

Accenture as Application Development Senior Analyst Apr 2015 to Till Date

COMPANY: ACCENTURE SOLUTIONS PVT LTD. Client: HENKEL International Gmbh, Germany

Project: Henkel NGO- EDI DEVELOPMENT & MAINTENANCE

Role: Application Development Senior Analyst

Year: Mar 2016-Current Date

RESPONSIBILITIES

This role is primarily focussed for the West Europe, North America, APAC and Latin America region in Adhesive, Laundry and Beauty Care business for the client.

Responsible for coordinating with business to understand the EDI requirements from respective customer and implement with the help of team.

Responsible for solution for all ALE and EDI related issues for document exchanges with partner via third party.

Responsible for handling high priority issues (P1 and P2 issues), P3 issues and Problem ticket with client's environment and resolve them with defined SLA.

Responsible for analysis, design, and implementation of customer/ 3PL requirements/change in business processes in the OtC-EDI area and Logistics-EDI area.

Responsible for creation and enhancement of EDI ABAP reports, FMs and EDI User Exits.

Responsible to resolve issues related to Sales Orders, Deliveries, Shipment, Billing, Pricing, special business processes and few others.

Responsible for creating Business Process, developing 850,856,810 and XML maps.

Responsible for performing MAP changes by co-ordinating with Business and customers and Setup Trading Partner.

Responsible for testing with OpenText (GXS) and SEEBURGER for translated message validity.

Responsible for scheduling, maintaining of jobs and used to do error analysis when the jobs failed in SAP.

Responsible for creation of partner profiles, ports in SAP to facilate the IDOC movement via RFC to third party.

Responsible for requirement gathering from business and preparing the functional design document.

Responsible for testing on the objects in the new system, optimizing the code and preparing Technical Design documents.

Created Conversion Exits and Change Pointer FMs for idoc creation and idoc value conversions.

Created IDoc Message Types, Logical System Names, RFC destinations, Ports, Segment, Basic IDOC Types, Message Types, Partner Profiles, Assigning Message Type to Basic IDOC Types, Maintaining Distribution Model, Message control, Checking IDOCs, Creating and assigning FMs to Logical Message, Define I/P method for Inbound and Outbound FMs, create process code, Generate Partner Profile, ALE Conversion Rule, Message Control.

Driven multiple automations such as different IDOC monitoring in SAP, being a part of Automation and Innovation team.

Responsible for resource development with knowledge transfer and other training activities.

Client: Starwood Hotels and Resorts Project: Starwood Production Support Role: Application Development Associate

Year: Jul 2015-Mar 2016 RESPONSIBILITIES

Responsible for modifying existing objects related to SAP FICO module as per requirement and resolve incidents.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Institute of Technical Education and Research, Bhuvaneshwar in 2014

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Odia				
German				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time